# **Robert Richards**

Full Stack Software Engineer

Full-stack web developer with a professional background in physical therapy, rehabilitation management, and leadership who enjoys challenge and working as a part of a team to create new technology. I am proficient in JavaScript, Python, and React. Driven by self and professional development to become a leader in the field. Motivated to create software and technology to help others accomplish their goals, and to improve the human experience.

#### **PROJECTS**

**Do you even Run?**— https://robrichardsdpt.github.io/running-app/

Full stack web application developed using ReactJS, JS, CSS, and Django. This application allows the user to track their runs and provides statistics and graphs for each. They can track their individual progress, and personal bests.

#### Instasham—

https://sei-tigers-404brainnotfound.github.io/group-project-front-end/#

This is an image upload site that allows you to manage your photos, update metadata (including description and tag), and see other account photos. Technologies used included JavaScript, axios, express, AWS, and React.

**ticTacToe**— https://robrichardsdpt.github.io/tic-tac-toe-client/

Allows a user to play a single player tic tac toe game. Allows the user to see if they win or tie that game. Keeps track of how many games they have played.

**Hiking tracker**— https://robrichardsdpt.github.io/hike-tracker-client/

Full stack web application developed using JavaScript, jquery, Mongoose, MongoDB, Express, AJAX, HTML, CSS, and Bootstrap. This application allows the user to track trails that they have hiked and store data for each one. They can modify each hike at any time. Perfect for keeping track of accomplishments toward hiking patches.

#### **RELEVANT EXPERIENCE**

# **General Assembly,** Remote — Software Engineering Immersive Fellow

August 2020 - PRESENT

12-week, 500+ hour training program focused in Git/Github, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, MongoDB, SQL, Python, React, Django, Bootstrap, etc.

Boston, MA
(919)745-7395
robrichardsdpt@gmail.com
LinkedIn:
www.linkedin.com/in/robertrichards-pt-dpt/
GitHub:
github.com/robrichardsdpt/
Porfolio:
https://robrichardsdpt.githu

#### **SKILLS**

b.io/portfolio/

Languages & Frameworks:
Python, JavaScript, Mongoose, jQuery, Node, Express, AJAX, HTML. CSS/Sass. Bootstrap

Management & Deployment: RSpec, Git, GitHub, Heroku, Command Line

Databases: SQL , PostgreSQL, MongoDB

Methodologies: Object Oriented Programming, MVC Pattern, Test-Driven Development, Responsive Design, Authentication, User Stories, ERDs, Wireframing, Agile Development/Scrum

#### **AWARDS**

Genesis Rehabilitation Services, Regional Business Excellence Award Recipient, 2015 APTA Mary McMillain Scholarship Winner, 2010 State University of New York Chancellor's Award Winner, 2007

**Education** General Assembly

#### **OTHER EXPERIENCES**

### **Physical Therapist**, Joint Ventures Physical Therapy-Boston

August 2016 - March 2020

- Provided 1:1 Physical Therapy evaluations, treatments, and reassessments of patients of various populations and diagnoses.
- Managed a caseload of 18 patients per day, and up to 80 per week.
- Project manager of the All Season performance program.
- Responsible for providing company wide education and social media content for two topics per year.
- Worked with the Administrative Assistant to ensure coverage for required services.

### Physical Therapist, Encompass Home Health, Boston

February 2019 - October 2019

- Provided physical therapy examination, treatment, and start of care for medically complex patients within the patient's home.
- Served the Boston region as the sole PT and oversaw the treatment of patients by 3 assistants.
- Participated and led interdisciplinary meetings within the area to determine appropriate intervention for the patient.

## **Director of Rehabilitation,** Genesis Rehabilitation - Boston

February 2014 - July 2016

- Directed a team consisting of Physical Therapists and Assistants, Occupational Therapists and Assistants, and Speech Language Pathologists in the delivery of care for short and long term residents at two locations.
- Managed the utilization and resources of various insurance policies and payor sources in the delivery of patient care.
- Performed HR related tasks, payroll, marketing, staffing, and various management related services for a 123 bed location in Brighton, MA and a 141 bed facility in Quincy, MA.

Software Engineering Immersive 8/2020 - 11/2020

University at Buffalo, The State University of New York Doctor of Physical Therapy, 5/2010 Bachelor of Science, Exercise Science and Bachelor of Arts, Psychology, 5/2007

Undergraduate GPA: 3.92/4.0 Graduate GPA: 4.0/4.0

## Professional Affiliations and Certifications

American Physical Therapy Association CPR and Basic Life Support USA Powerlifting Member Spartan Race Group Exercise and Obstacle Specialist

## Other Leadership Experiences

Physical Therapy and Rehabilitation Science Class President Human Gross Anatomy and Comparative Primate Anatomy Teaching Assistant